

Jennifer Carey

Experience Stategy & Design

+1-480-686-6752 | jennifercarey@gmail.com | jenniferjamescarey.com

SUMMARY

15 years in tech, primarily in UX, with extensive international experience.

My favorite challenges have been building a UX practice from the ground up in a country where UX didn't yet exist, developing a UX consulting methodology, crafting a corporate culture, and solving the puzzle of attracting and developing talent in a limited market.

I am passionate about UX practices and principles and how they can be applied broadly, not only to software but strategically, to organizations, physical spaces, and ultimately, to how we live our lives.

EXPERIENCE

Jennifer James Consulting, Principal Consultant 2010-Present, San Francisco, USA

Primarily focused on parenting two small children with occasional freelance projects, and continuous intensive communication study.

element^n, Director of Professional Services 2003-2010, Beirut, Lebanon

Worked with 3 other partners to grow element^n from 5 to 50, eventually winning awards and capital investment. Led our web and UX consulting team on web and intranet projects from concept to build in Bahrain, Sudan, Kuwait, and Dubai.

Siemens, Technical Writer & Documentation Manager 2000-2003, Milan, Italy

Introduced User Centered Design and transitioned documentation from narrative to scenario based.

Generated support for a documentation team which I recruited, hired, mentored and managed.

Infocom, Freelance Technical Writer 1995-1999, Durham, North Carolina

Provided short to mid term technical documentation to companies including Siemens, Glaxo Wellcome, United States Postal Service.

PROFILE

Big picture, strategic thinker; generalist; servant leader; creative and logical; analytical; catalyst for change; student of empathy; fan of agile and lean.

SEEKING

The chance to make real positive change in partnership with others; an opportunity to go deep with UX and wide where needed.

METHODS

One-on-one interviews; focus groups; contextual inquiry; affinity diagrams; card sorting; personas; scenarios; stories; consensus workshops; collaborative design; usability testing; low fi prototyping.

EDUCATION

BA English American Literature, University of California, Santa Cruz